Hi and welcome to Learn WordPress. In<br />this video, we are going to explore the
Columns block. The Columns block is a<br />container block, which can be used to
create a variety of custom layouts, and<br />it opens up a world of design
possibilities. The Columns block allows<br />you to insert text, media and other
types of content into up to six columns.<br />And when used one after another, the
Columns block creates a cool grid<br />effect. To add a Columns block, click on
the Inserter and type columns or you<br />could type forward slash columns and
select it from there. You can choose the<br />number and the size of the columns that
you want to start with. The beauty of<br />the Columns block is that you can add
other blocks into each column. For<br />example, you can create the Columns
block to add structure, and then add<br />Image blocks, Heading blocks and
Paragraph blocks. You can also create<br />this type of design by adding a Cover
block to each column. There is a<br />parent/child relationship between the
main Columns block and the individual<br />columns that form part of the parent
block. When you click on the alignment<br />icon, you will be able to change the
alignment of your block to wide width or<br />full width. Did you know that you can
also duplicate columns? Let's select the<br />third column in the Columns block. When
you click on the three vertical dots,<br />you have an option to duplicate.
Duplicating a design will save you a lot<br />of time and effort. When you select an
individual column, you also have the<br />option in the block toolbar to use the
arrows to move the column to a new<br />position. But you also have the option
in the list view to drag and drop a<br />column where you want. If you wanted to
add another column, you could merely<br />click on the Inserter between two
columns to add a new column or you can<br />select the parent block and then open up
your sidebar settings. And at the top of<br />the sidebar settings, you will notice it
says columns where you can increase or<br />decrease the amount of columns in your
Columns block. Then below that, keep<br />stack selected if you want the columns
to stack on top of each other when<br />viewed on a mobile device. The Columns
block allows you to change the colours<br />of both the parent block or individual
columns. So let's go ahead and change<br />the background colour for example. There
are also various typography options<br />worth exploring, such as font family,
appearance and letter spacing. You might<br />even decide to change the size of your
Columns block.
Below dimensions you can adjust the<br />padding or the space around the content
of the block, and if you click on unlink<br />sides, you can set different values for
the top, right, bottom and left. You can<br />also change the margin of the block,
which is the space surrounding the<br />Columns block at the top and the bottom.
When you click on the ellipses, you can<br />also select Block spacing which allows
you to modify the space between columns.
Lastly, you may even decide to add a<br />border or change the radius of the
Columns block.
Another great feature is that you can<br />transform other blocks to a Columns
block and even a Columns block to a<br />Group block. So as you can see, you can
achieve any custom design using the<br />Columns block from introducing your
team, displaying different types of<br />media or even creating a pricing table.
Enjoy designing with the Columns block<br />and visit Learn WordPress for more
tutorials and training material.